<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sepiropht</title>
    <link>https://sepiropht.me/</link>
    <description>Recent content on sepiropht</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 14:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sepiropht.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How I Back Up My Data</title>
      <link>https://sepiropht.me/posts/how-do-i-backup-my-homelab/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sepiropht.me/posts/how-do-i-backup-my-homelab/</guid>
      <description>In my last article, I explained how Docker saved me when my Raspberry Pi, which hosted all my services, suddenly failed. Indeed, Docker allows for good compartmentalization of configurations and data, and lets you choose where to store them, which in my case was an external hard drive. In case of a failure, you just need to take the hard drive and connect it to another machine, and you&amp;rsquo;re done.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why i love docker</title>
      <link>https://sepiropht.me/posts/why-i-love-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 12:19:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sepiropht.me/posts/why-i-love-docker/</guid>
      <description>1. The problem This morning, I had a problem: my server, a Raspberry Pi 2 bought in 2016, no longer starts. I used this old machine to host many services (WireGuard, Nextcloud, Bitwarden, ODPS server, etc.).&#xA;After a few unsuccessful attempts, I gave up on the idea of repairing it and decided to use another one of my servers instead. I unplugged the external hard drive from my Raspberry Pi and plugged it into my other server.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blüdhaven</title>
      <link>https://sepiropht.me/projects/bludhaven/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sepiropht.me/projects/bludhaven/</guid>
      <description>History Blüdhaven was a former whaling town, which was officially incorporated as a &amp;ldquo;Commonwealth&amp;rdquo; in 1912. The town had a generally poor socio-economic populace, owing in part to failed efforts to transform itself into a manufacturing and shipping center.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydra</title>
      <link>https://sepiropht.me/projects/hydra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sepiropht.me/projects/hydra/</guid>
      <description>Motto Cut off one head and two will take their place</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tatooine</title>
      <link>https://sepiropht.me/projects/tatooine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sepiropht.me/projects/tatooine/</guid>
      <description>A long time ago in a galaxy far, far away&amp;hellip;. A project was planned, but never completed</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
